Kenneth Ly

Computer Science Student

Plano, TX 75024 (505) 417-2653 Kenneth.ly19@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kenneth-ly-KLL505

Github: https://github.com/KLL505 **Portfolio:** https://kll505.github.io/

Summary

I'm a computer science student enrolled at the University of Texas at Dallas with a 3.9 GPA and Dean's List accreditation, focused on building experiences and relationships to help guide me into my professional career. I have been programming for 6 years and am experienced in C++, C, C#, Java, and Python, and have worked with ASP.net core, Springboot, React, and VUE.js frameworks. Additionally I have 2 years of professional expierence working as a web application developer and software engineering intern but is always open to exploring new oppurtunities and learn new skills.

EXPERIENCE

USAA, Plano, TX - Software Engineering Intern

May 2023 - Augest 2023

- Developed and enhanced logging capabilities of a Gradle Spring Boot Java application, leading to improved visibility into system behavior and debugging efficiency.
- Conducted API testing using Postman, ensuring the reliability and functionality of RESTful endpoints, and effectively communicating test results to the development team.
- Helped Implement and configure the ELK stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana) to set up real-time monitoring and centralized log management, facilitating proactive issue detection and resolution.
- Developed mock objects and utilized Mockito to simulate dependencies, enabling isolated testing of individual components.
- Utilized JUnit assertions to validate expected outcomes and ensure the reliability of the application's core functionalities, following test driven development principles.
- Utilized AWS DynamoDB Streams to capture and process real-time changes to DynamoDB tables, enabling reactive behaviors and event-driven architecture.
- Actively participated in an Agile development enviorment involving daily scrum meetings, sprint
 retrospectives, and project increment planning, while utilizing project management tools such as JIRA and
 Mural.

Ayoka Systems, Arlington, TX - Web Applications Developer

May 2022 - May 2023

- Worked with a small team in the development of web applications using frameworks such as ASP.Net core and VUE.js
- Worked heavily with C#, HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, and Typescript languages for programming.
- Interacted with a Microsoft SQL Server and Postgres relational database, performing queries and uploads to manage data for the application
- Utilized Javascript libraries and frameworks including AG Grid, and jQuery, and used AJAX and JSON coding to maintain the front of the application
- Designed code that strictly followed MVC architecture to address separations of concern and the flow of the application
- Troubleshoot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- Adapted quickly to a constantly changing, deadline-driven environment following the Agile Software Development model
- Used a variety of new technologies including Node.js, Firebase, Supabase, and AWS
- Used Git to maintain the organization of our team's code and manage versions of the application

The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX - Teaching Assistant

August 2022 - December 2022

- Assisted in the course "ECS1100 Introduction to Engineering and Computer Science"
- Helped professor with classroom management and document coordination to maintain a positive learning environment.
- Met with students outside of class to answer questions, explain difficult concepts, and address individual concerns.
- Delivered clear, effective feedback to improve the quality and efficiency of student-written computer programs.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX - Bachelors in Computer Science

August 2021 - PRESENT

- Part of the Deans List which is the top 10% of all undergraduate students
- 3.97 GPA with 76 credit hours
- Expected to graduate in the winter of 2024

SKILLS

- Java
- C/C++
- Python
- jQuery
- Vue.Js
- ASP.NET

Springboot

TypeScript

- **ELK Stack**
- SQL
- Mockito
- Junit4
- **Unit Testing**
- Postman API Testing
- **Object Oriented Programming**

- Data Structures and Algorithr
- Relational Databases
- MVC Architecture
- Agile Software Development
- Debugging
- Mentoring
- Photography
- Music Production

PROJECTS

International Storage Tank Management System - Ayoka Systems

Worked with a small team on the full stack of a central system used by an international storage tank shipping company to keep track of all their operations. I was tasked with developing many significant features, creating unit tests, debugging, and helping implement an AWS S3 bucket into the application for file storage. The technologies of this application included ASP.net Core, BootStrap, AGgrid, and Microsoft SQL server.

Simple Network Database - Personal

This program was built in Linux using sockets and client-server architecture to emulate a remote network database. The program allows clients to connect to a server by giving a DNS and port number. Once connected, clients can then store, access, and delete records (which is a 512-byte string that consists of a name and 10-digit ID) within this server's database stored in a local file on the server's machine. Multiple clients can connect to the server at once and perform actions synchronously due to the implementation of multithreading and locks.

Think Better Bot - Personal

A personalized discord bot created for my personal discord server to help me and my friends study and solve problems. The bot uses the wolfram alpha API to answer questions, solve step-by-step math problems, hold conversations relating to a problem, and provide detailed information on given topics. It was built with typescript and uses functionality from the discord.js API, the wolfram alpha API, the xml2js library, and the cross-fetch library.

*Additional Personal projects available to view on my GitHub/Portfolio